<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>let's impute</title><link>https://letsimpute.com/</link><description>Programming and Data</description><atom:link href="https://letsimpute.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:koryd2718@gmail.com"&gt;koryd&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 06:44:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Data Engineering with Airflow and Azure</title><link>https://letsimpute.com/posts/data-engineering-with-airflow-and-azure/</link><dc:creator>koryd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Data Engineering with Airflow and Azure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TOC&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;coming soon...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work I work in a strictly Microsoft shop. Tools like SSIS and SSAS are what I spend most of my day slaving over. Although these tools are powerful, they are more akin to the &lt;code&gt;no-code&lt;/code&gt; methodologies. I wanted to grow my knowledge and work with the tools I am excited about. I love code, so &lt;code&gt;no-code&lt;/code&gt; is almost a bad word to me.
Python is an amazing language and perfectly suited to get started with data processing. Although python itself has some issues, you can make use of great libraries to do what you want with most of the pain points of the language abstracted away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Credit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am mostly following the &lt;a href="https://www.startdataengineering.com/post/data-engineering-project-for-beginners-batch-edition/"&gt;excellent blog written by Joseph Machado&lt;/a&gt;. However, I hope to add a new perspective to a few things. Joseph's blog describes how to setup an airflow pipeline that uses AWS services to store and process the data. I will use Microsoft Azure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Azure?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just complained about Microsoft products above, why do I want to use Azure? Well, I have free credits that I can use from my work. These credits are not being used at my job, and I have been given permission to use them for personal use. Thanks job! Azure is competitive with AWS, but has some quirks to overcome. Many of the services on AWS are also available on Azure. See this reference for a general idea: &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/architecture/aws-professional/services"&gt;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/architecture/aws-professional/services&lt;/a&gt;. However, I have noticed that things are not as easy and switching S3 for AzureBlobStorage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to learn by blogging. I will setup this to help me not only teach the reader, but also to help myself put what I have learned together. Please join me on this journey and let me know what your thoughts are!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>airflow</category><category>azure</category><category>data engineering</category><guid>https://letsimpute.com/posts/data-engineering-with-airflow-and-azure/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 18:06:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>